More Spice from the makers of Fritz the Cat!
Heavy Traffic is a animation, comedy, drama film directed by Ralph Bakshi.
A white dropout struggles to become a cartoonist and filmmaker, drawing
inspiration from the harsh, gritty world around him.
Still sharing his rundown apartment with his middle-aged parents, an oafish slob of an Italian father and a ditzy nutcase of a Jewish mother, he's ridiculed and looked down upon
by his friends, hypocrites who run with violent gangs and the Italian Mafia, and a shallow Black girl who makes her living downtown with the pimps and pushers.
The cartoonist gets a chance to pitch a film idea to a movie mogul, but the story proves too outrageous: a
far-future Earth, depleted by war and pollution, where a mutant antihero challenges and kills God.
Michael Corleone, played by Joseph Kaufmann.
Carole, played by Beverly Hope Atkinson.
Angelo "Angie" Corleone (voice), played by Frank De Kova.
Ida Corleone (voice), played by Terry Haven.
Molly (voice), played by Mary Dean Lauria.
Rosalyn Schecter (voice), played by Jacqueline Mills.
Heavy Traffic is a 1973 American live-action/adult animated
drama film written and directed by Ralph Bakshi.
The film, which begins, ends, and occasionally combines with live-action, explores the often surreal fantasies of a young
New York City cartoonist named Michael Corleone, using pinball imagery as a metaphor for inner-city life.
Heavy Traffic was Bakshi and producer Steve Krantz's
follow-up to the film Fritz the Cat.
Though producer Krantz made varied attempts to produce an R-rated
film, Heavy Traffic was given an X rating by the MPAA.
The film received largely positive reviews and is widely
considered to be Bakshi's biggest critical success.
The film explores themes of virgin, sexual
frustration, surrealism, urban life, marijuana.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.